Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
♪The white sail came too late♪
♪Where did he go?♪
♪Snow veils the mountains♪
♪Love endures beyond life and death♪
♪A black chess piece♪
♪Whose game did he stumble into?♪
♪All his life, there's no escape♪
♪In ten thousand years, what will still remain?♪
♪Will anyone still love with an unchanging heart?♪
♪I will remember♪
♪Those days long past♪
♪As the wind drifts with the white sail♪
♪Ten thousand years ago♪
♪Did you once walk this shore?♪
♪Why can't our bond be severed in this life?♪
♪I am lost yet willing♪
♪Still I love you with a steadfast heart♪
♪Until all things fade away♪
♪The stars will remember us♪
[Love & Crown]
[Adapted from the novel "My Queen" by Xie Lounan]
[Episode 21]
I didn't expect Xiao Huan
to be such a romantic.
Don't move.
How could this happen?
Sorry to disappoint you.
I've woken up.
This can't be!
How could my Illusion-Butterfly Powder fail?
How is it that you're both standing here?
The Frost Reed can cure any poison.
It seems
your investigation wasn't thorough enough.
Cangcang!
Zhong Lin!
Are you all right?
We're fine.
Thanks to the Puppet Incense that Xiao Qianqing brought,
we managed to control one of the servants.
Good.
The antidote. Quickly.
Let's go.
Release the branch leader.
And we'll leave you both with intact bodies!
Clear the way.
Make way.
Hurry!
Xiao Huan,
do you really think you can escape?
I'll give you one more chance.
Hand over the Moon-Eclipse,
or I'll make sure all of you lose your senses
and perish with your meridians severed.
Zhong Lin.
Insolent.
Protector, have mercy!
I only sought to present
the Moon-Eclipse to you.
Is that so?
My sources tell me you intend
to become the Ghost King yourself.
Die!
Luo Xianxue?
Luo.
I'm glad you're safe.
That day,
I watched you be engulfed in flames with my own eyes.
Father sent someone to retrieve your body,
and they found a severed finger on it as well.
I thought
I'd never see you again.
How did you escape?
There was a cellar in the liquor storage.
I hid there
and barely survived.
You never came
looking for me.
I knew
His Majesty saw me as a thorn in his side.
If I appeared recklessly,
I'd only bring you trouble.
So,
I planned
to wander the world.
And now you've appeared out of nowhere.
Do you intend to assassinate him?
Why?
I don't want
to see you hurt,
suffering,
or endangered because of him.
Cangcang,
he's your tribulation.
Don't let yourself get entangled with him anymore.
If you can't make up your mind,
I can help.
Luo,
so much has happened
between him and me since you left.
It's not
as simple as you think.
Even I didn't expect some things.
He and I...
Nobody can decide our matters for me.
I overstepped.
That's not what I meant.
Luo, I...
Cangcang.
Have you forgotten?
You saved my life.
Protecting you
is my lifelong duty.
I don't want to see you harmed in any way.
I heard they raided an evildoer's base around here.
Many missing children were found.
Many of them were silenced.
He moved!
They say
you're dying.
I won't allow it.
Luo Xianxue,
you are not to die
without my permission.
I, Luo Xianxue, swear to the heavens.
From now on, I belong to Ling Cangcang.
No matter how hard it gets,
I will stay strong
for Ling Cangcang.
No matter how hard it gets,
I will stay strong
for Ling Cangcang.
Cangcang,
it's for you
that I crawled my way out of that fire.
Luo,
ever since you joined the Ling family,
you've always been a brother to me.
Do you remember
the vow I made when I entered the palace?
I will protect everyone in the Ling family.
I've never changed.
It's just...
With Xiao Huan,
I now...
So,
no matter how much he hurts you,
you won't hurt him back.
Is that right?
Luo,
I think there are many misunderstandings
between you two.
It will take time to clear them up.
All right.
If that's the case,
we'll talk next time.
Good.
Cangcang,
I remember you've always loved
pear blossom honey since you were little.
I brought some
especially for you.
I didn't expect
you still remember after all this time.
Of course.
Try it while it's warm.
It's the taste I remember.
It's been...
Cangcang!
Luo Xianxue.
I know why you came.
If you really wanted to be dead,
you wouldn't show up.
Let's cut the chatter.
Hand over the Moon-Eclipse
and face your fate.
Do you know what you're saying?
There will be
a battle between us.
Have you thought about
what will happen to Cangcang?
I will never hurt her.
You already have.
You know Ling Xuefeng is using you
to rebuild the Lingbi Sect,
yet you willingly serve as his dog.
You know how Cangcang feels about me,
yet you help Ling Xuefeng to kill me.
What do you expect
Cangcang to think or do?
Enough talk.
Fight me!
Stop!
Cangcang...
You lied to me.
You weren't supposed to be...
I've used inner force to remove the sedative in the pear blossom honey.
Your "death" was flawless.
You couldn't have done it alone.
What's really going on?
Cangcang,
you and Father
saved my life.
I must obey
his command.
My father?
What order did my father give you?
He must die
today.
You won't succeed!
Cangcang,
move aside!
The Xiaoxing Guards are already lying in wait.
You can't do anything to me.
Luo Xianxue,
you loyally serve Grand Tutor Ling.
But sadly,
you're a fool.
Do you know what Grand Tutor Ling has done?
Whatever he does,
it's all for the Ling clan
and Cangcang.
Is it?
Do you know Grand Tutor Ling
poisoned Ling Cangcang to force His Majesty
to give her the cure?
Were his actions really for Ling Cangcang's sake?
What?
My father...
Was it
the pear blossom honey?
Grand Tutor Ling brought this pear blossom honey today.
I added four spoonfuls as instructed.
♪The rouge spilling into old snow...♪
Luo Xianxue,
surrender yourself.
Never!
Wait.
♪Oaths wither at the root of the tongue♪
♪Only a wisp of smoke binds the butterfly...♪
Your Majesty.
Let him go.
Let him go?
Cangcang!
Go!
I never want to see you again.
Leave!
♪And to share the red kiss of a blade upon the neck♪
♪We brew our hottest tears...♪
Very well.
Leave.
♪The cinnabar between my brows has turned to icy flakes♪
♪The empty pouch you gave♪
♪Is filled with my grief♪
♪If yearning for each other is a tribulation♪
♪I should've broken my sword and rejected the invitation♪
♪So much for vows of growing old together...♪
So it was all
my father's doing...
You should go back.
I need some time to myself.
♪Using the sweetest curse♪
♪To build the coldest graveyard♪
♪Buried under the parasol tree during the sorrowful night rain♪
♪Are destined to meet on that autumn day of White Dew♪
♪Shattering glazed fantasy with these sewn shoes♪
♪Using the sweetest curse♪
♪To build the coldest graveyard♪
♪Buried under the parasol tree during the sorrowful night rain♪
♪Are destined to meet on that autumn day of White Dew♪
♪And to share the red kiss of a blade upon the neck...♪
I wish
to resign of my own accord.
I only ask that Your Majesty
will be merciful
and spare
my only daughter.
[Qi]
They've returned at last.
We welcome the return of His Majesty and Her Majesty.
It's been a while, everyone.
I hope all has been well.
I dare to ask,
Your Highness, how much longer
will you govern on behalf of His Majesty?
Well...
His Majesty's health has greatly improved
but still requires rest.
You'll have to deal with me for a while longer,
Grand Tutor Ling.
His Majesty and Her Majesty share a deep and enduring love.
It is a blessing for Great Qi.
Enough of these words.
Save them
for when His Majesty returns from the outer palace
to hear it himself.
Now, let us discuss the situation in Xuzhou.
The disaster in Xuzhou
has been temporarily contained.
Sadly, Song Lanxi
was killed.
Mr. Song was killed?
Mr. Li,
I have failed you.
Lanxi sacrificed himself for the country.
I pray Your Highness will investigate the culprits behind the unrest.
Rest assured.
It is my duty.
That said,
the position of Governor of Xuzhou remains vacant.
There is no suitable candidate in Xuzhou.
From what I know,
the former Governor
was once under Grand Tutor Ling's tutelage.
Might you have
any suggestions
for the new Governor,
Grand Tutor Ling?
I never expected
the Governor of Xuzhou
to commit such unforgivable acts!
He ignored my warnings.
It brings shame upon me.
Indeed.
I was also taken aback.
Mr. Li,
you've returned to court.
I entrust you to recommend
a governor for Xuzhou.
Yes, Your Highness.
My Lord,
His Majesty and Her Majesty have arrived at the outer palace.
Still no word from Xianxue?
No.
We grew up together.
My mission is to protect Cangcang.
But now,
she no longer needs your protection.
Who said that?
His Majesty.
Then what am I to do?
Do whatever
you wish.
Be carefree and at ease.
Isn't that a good thing?
Can I?
You can.
♪Her hairpin sways♪
♪Thoughts linger on...♪
I think so too.
♪The warmth of your touch♪
♪Turns time into a gentle circle♪
♪Pear blossoms dream beneath the snow♪
♪Steam from tea wafts♪
♪Memories resurface♪
♪Ink seeps across the frayed edge of the page♪
♪The letter from that year♪
♪Hidden inside its creases♪
♪Is a spring not yet dried...♪
How is it?
How is what?
The taste when you kissed my forehead just now.
♪Drifting, falling, endless and tender♪
♪Through every season, every year, every day♪
I...
There's a lingering aroma of liquor on my lips.
Would you like to taste it?
♪Dark hair twines into a thread of fate♪
♪Drifting, falling, endless and tender♪
♪Through every season, every year, every day♪
♪The scent of pear blossoms fills the garden again♪
♪Fills the garden again♪
♪Frost on her hairpin♪
♪Moon in my palms...♪
Sweet,
but slightly astringent.
♪As pear blossom season comes again♪
♪The scent of pear blossoms fills the garden again♪
♪Fills the garden again♪
Young Master,
what are you...
Answer me.
Did you really poison
Young Lady's pear blossom honey?
Did you?
I can't believe it's true.
Father actually meant to harm Cangcang.
No.
He had his reasons.
Everything he does is for her
and the Ling clan.
He never meant her harm.
Then, answer this.
If that person hadn't given her the antidote,
what would have happened?
You're gambling with her life!
Luo Xianxue!
I pulled you back from the brink of death
and took you in.
Is this how you repay me?
I am Cangcang's father.
Everything I do
is for her good.
Xianxue,
this is the path she must walk.
All we can do
is pave the way for her
to travel steadily
and far.
I know your heart aches.
As a father, so does mine.
But this is the truth she longs for
and the reality she must face.
I beg
Your Majesty
to spare the Ling clan
and Luo Xianxue.
I offer myself
as Your Majesty's consort.
May Your Majesty grant my request.
Xiao Huan,
let him go!
Let him go.
I'm sorry.
I was the one who was wrong.
I thought I was protecting you,
yet I brought you nothing but harm.
Cangcang,
I swear to the heavens.
From this day forth,
I will never let you suffer
even the slightest harm.
How did I end up here?
Your Majesty,
I'll announce your arrival right away.
Don't bother.
The Emperor returned
to court today.
Yet, my son still has the nerve to sleep soundly in his residence.
Your Majesty,
please mind your health.
What...
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Where did you come from?
Dishevelled
and sneaking about.
What are you doing at the Prince of Yuzhang's manor?
The night was young,
and we made merry together.
What else
did you think we did?
You...
Your Majesty.
[Linghe Hall]
We welcome Her Majesty's return.
[Fate's rise and fall heed no one's will]
[Where fate is sown, the heart makes its own choice]
Look at mine.
See how high it is.
Mine's higher.
Zhong Lin,
you brought me out of the palace.
Is there something you want to tell me?
I...
Cangcang.
You...
What do you want to say?
Nothing.
You seemed to be in low spirits,
so I thought a kite flying outing might cheer you up.
Cangcang,
you've seemed unhappy lately.
What's troubling you?
I was thinking about my father.
Grand Tutor Ling?
Since our return from Jiangzhou
and after meeting Luo Xianxue,
you've been acting strangely.
What happened?
It wasn't until today
that I pieced everything together.
It turns out
the mastermind behind all this
was him.
Xiao Huan never told me
about everything my father did.
I think
he wanted to protect me
and feared I wouldn't be able to bear it.
These past few days, I've been thinking.
When did Father
who cared for
and protected me so much change?
How could he do such things?
Cangcang,
you're his only daughter.
He must love you.
But how much
of that love is genuine
and how much is self-serving,
I can no longer tell.
He was certain
Xiao Huan would use the Frost Reed to save me.
If I could successfully carry a child,
he could support my child
to ascend the throne.
So
what do we do now?
The Grand Tutor has set his mind to this...
What does His Majesty plan to do with him?
Caught between the two,
what should you do?
Xiao Huan is a wise ruler of Great Qi.
He is a good emperor for the people.
To protect Great Qi,
the stability of the nation,
and the well-being of the people,
I must stand alongside Xiao Huan
as his equal.
As for my father...
I only hope
he can still change his ways.
But I haven't figured out how to face him yet.
Cangcang,
he will.
The Grand Tutor surely will.
Shall we go
fly kites?
Don't dwell on it.
Let all these worries and sorrows
fly away like kites.
All right?
Come on.
Come on!
That boy runs fast.
Yes.
- Be careful. - Careful.
Wait for me!
It flies so high!
[Taiji Hall]
Today,
I wish to discuss
the abolition of the status verification system in Jiangzhou.
In addition,
to implement temporary centralized status verification nationwide
and gradually abolish the system.
Does anyone
have objections?
Your Majesty,
while
the temporary system might solve
immediate concerns,
it risks encouraging negative practices.
Please consider carefully, Your Majesty.
What negative practices?
Well...
Your Majesty,
Minister Xing believes the root
of the vagrants' issues
lies in registration and taxation.
Centralizing the registration
might cause taxation problems.
Therefore,
this can't continue.
Since you brought up taxation,
I've also given the matter some thought.
This tax system was set during the reign of the previous emperor.
Shouldn't it be improved to suit the times?
Your Majesty,
this tax system has been in place for many decades.
It has its reasons to exist.
It won't do to change it
on a whim.
I believe
what Your Majesty has said
is reasonable.
Mr. Li is right.
I also support Your Majesty's proposal.
Prince of Yuzhang, what are your views?
As His Majesty and Grand Tutor Ling said,
the tax system hasn't changed for decades.
But Great Qi's development
never stops.
I believe
this is the time to break the old ways
and reform taxation.
Prince of Yuzhang and I are of the same opinion.
The current tax system
has many types of levies
which prompt frequent corruption by officials.
I have also
considered simplifying
the collections
and taxing by acreage instead.
Of course,
all this is still under discussion.
If any minister has ideas,
please present them to me.
Since no one else has anything to say,
we'll end
today's session here.
You're grinning without reason.
What cunning scheme
is your wise self plotting now?
I just think
you were especially impressive today.
As a matter of fact,
it has been a long time
since we had a proper conversation.
Feel free to enjoy this advantage you have earned.
Well,
what do you think of my idea?
If the tax policies are simplified,
officials will find it harder to cheat,
so revenue should increase.
More importantly,
the people's tax burden will lessen.
It is indeed a good proposal.
However...
However,
the status verification issue
only treats the symptoms, not the cause.
We'll take it slow.
Reform
takes time.
I heard you stopped Her Majesty's birth-control tea.
You know about that?
My mother cares about you having an heir
much more than I do.
I heard
she is eager to find a princess consort for you.
What do you say?
Would you like me to find you a few?
I do regret
meddling and saving you.
Look.
Victory is mine.
Your Majesty,
is it true that you can roast pears?
Yes.
This is a recipe my mother invented.
When I was little,
I remember often
roasting pears with my master
and father...
The Grand Tutor roasts pears too?
I haven't roasted them
in a while as well.
Father.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Please be seated.
You as well, Your Majesty.
Let me tell you something.
Only the Jinye pears
from Shuiquan Village are best for roasting.
They are full of juice.
Once they're grilled,
spread some
of your favourite pear blossom honey on them.
You used to love it
as a child.
♪Who walks lone through storm and snow♪
♪Reading every warmth and chill♪
♪Of the heart?♪
♪Who stands proud against a thousand weights♪
♪Grace only a mask he wears?♪
♪My blade sweeps the heavens♪
♪Blood once drenched♪
♪My armor and charging steed♪
♪I know what it means to let go♪
♪When to step in, when to hold back♪
♪A broken blade cuts through♪
♪Years of winter and summer♪
♪Enemy flags burn to ash like gauze♪
♪Yet my heart still bears the scars of rise and fall♪
♪I'm willing to wield my sword with you and burn the waning moon♪
♪I'm willing to brave all storms with you, boiling with passion♪
♪I'm willing to break my wings and become the blade in your hand♪
♪I'm willing to write with you this torn, enduring page of history♪
♪I'm willing to travel thousands of miles, seeking your ambition♪
♪I'm willing to give my life to keep you safe for a lifetime♪
♪I'm willing to sing through every farewell and wait for you another thousand years♪
♪I'm willing to live and die with you, my one and only wish in this lifetime♪